hi let's talk about apple the right to
repair movement and this recent verge
article that came out thank you for
those who sent it to me to comment on
this um here it is apple shipped me a 79
pound iphone repair kit to fix a 1.1
ounce battery i'm starting to think
apple doesn't want us to repair them um
and this is absolutely hilarious so
let's go through it sean hollister um
from the verge and apple must be joking
that's how i felt again and again as i
jumped through hoop after ridiculous
hoop to replace the battery in my iphone
mini part of that was the repair process
mostly it was how difficult accent apple
actually makes it to get there last
month apple launched his self-service
repair program letting us customers fix
broken screens batteries and cameras the
latest iphones using apple's own parts
of the tool for the first time ever i've
never successfully repaired a phone but
this time i'm with an official repair
manual and genuine parts i'd make it
right that apple would even let me buy
these parts let alone read its manuals
and rent its tools is a major change of
pace for the company for years yes of
course apple has been lobbying against
the right to repair movement of course
everyone i think all of my audience is
already following lewis rossman but if
you're not of course he's on the um
leading edge of the right to repair
movement so
i'll link in lewis if you don't if you
don't know about lewis come on seriously
um but having tried the repair process i
can i actually can't recommend it at all
and as i have a sneaking suspicion that
apple likes it that way so as it turns
out this article is actually pretty
disingenuous and doesn't really um show
it in the real light it doesn't explain
what the real problems and issues um uh
anyway basically what sean is uh
complaining about is that he ordered you
can actually rent now the official apple
tools for repairing iphones and they
will actually ship you know you can rent
them for i think it's a week and you
have to send them back after that or you
can actually buy them i'll show you this
uh in a minute but anyway he's basically
having a whinge that to fix his iphone
sure you can now get access to the
genuine parts the official apple repair
manual and
the uh official apple repair tools to do
it so he rented them and he's
complaining that they came in these huge
two huge pelican cases like this and
you'll see why in a minute so he
unpacked them all and here is all of the
tools and it doesn't look fantastic as
you'd expect these are apples you know
proper internal repair tools i haven't
just hastily put these together to
satisfy the right to repair movement
these are the tools they actually use
in-house at the authorized apple repair
centers and it comes with like the
ring-bound manual and like and all the
tools and the proper presses to put the
screens back and everything it's
absolutely fantastic now first of all
you have to actually give apple credit
uh for doing this they have actually
released all you know well not
everything but they're really you know
you can actually buy and rent their
tools and the official parts and the
official service manuals and everything
and i'll link in here's the official
press release it was april uh 22nd
genuine apple parts and tools can now be
purchased by us customers as i said you
can also
rent them as well anyway we won't go
into that but basically uh they link you
over to the apple self service repair
site and you can start with the repair
manual and sure enough you can actually
go in here and here's the manuals they
haven't released the macbook manuals but
apparently they're coming and other mac
products i don't know but uh yeah at the
moment they've um so sort of you know
most of the latest called last what two
or three gens of iphones or something
you can get the manuals and sure enough
here it is the iphone 13 pro
repair manual this is their official
in-house repair manual i'll link it in
it's very comprehensive as you'd expect
of any in-house repair manual ever you
know the size of apple they've had a
team of people actually uh put these
together and they're very impressive and
it goes how i don't know how many
81 pages long right and then they've got
all the individual part numbers and then
all the part numbers for all the tools
and everything else right it's
incredibly impressive and here's all the
stuff you need and i've done like
in-house documents like this as well um
at companies i've worked for and this is
you know this is what um companies do
for their own in-house it's even how to
unbox the tools and everything look at
these
really professional level uh repair
tools and this is what you'd expect
these companies to actually do and you
can buy these as i'll show you in a
minute and you can also rent them as
well and all the safety concerns and
everything and then how to like replace
the screen and replace the battery and
replace the camera and all sorts of
things it's not how to troubleshoot to a
component level um but you know look
it's like it's it's serious this is
absolutely fantastic so you've got to
give hats off to apple for actually
releasing their in-house manuals for
these i i can't believe these didn't
leak out actually considering that some
of the schematics and other
things have leaked out but this is
absolutely brilliant right and then sure
enough if you go over to their apple um
it's actually
selfservicerepair.com they did a whole
domain for it and everything and they've
got um here it is so you can only do the
iphone at the moment and they're the
models available and here's the type of
stuff they let you repair the battery
the bottom speaker the camera the
display um but you know if your
lightning connector breaks or whatever i
get like
you're screwed i guess right so there's
only limited um things that that they
actually let you uh change right and so
the camera here is like the camera
itself is 111 bucks these would be
yankee prices right replace part return
credit what's that after your repair
return your replaced part to receive
credit that's interesting i just noticed
that um that must be so that they
they don't want these parts in the
second hand market they don't want
people to like resell them on ebay or
something like that but while you'd
resell it if it's broken i
i don't know anyway um yeah you can
actually get a credit if you actually
return it look at that so they've really
gone to town and they've got like their
proper like adhesive uh displays to put
the display back on and stuff like that
you can buy like all the individual
scrolls and the little um cowl in that
goes over i don't know the backing or
something for it um so this is this is
really impressive let's have a look at
the display the display cost 267 bucks i
don't know if this is all good value
compared to like aftermarket ones i
assume not right but but the fact that
they you can just add these to the cart
and then then you can buy them is
absolutely fantastic but anyway look at
this i'll show you all the like the
spudgers and the you know the tools and
everything and sure enough here's the
display press down here they'll sell
that to you for 216 bucks i think that's
actually really good value and the
heated display removal fixture 256 bucks
i reckon that's an absolute bargain
actually of course you wouldn't buy
these if you just joe average and want
to fix your phone one off right of
course but if you're running like an
iphone repair business or something i
would totally buy these right that's an
absolute bargain for like the that
quality for 256 bucks are you kidding me
i'd buy that in a heartbeat if i was
repairing these things you can go into
business fixing um you know iphones and
get all the original apple parts and and
guides and everything fantastic hats off
see now here's the problem right with
the verge article is that he's basically
complaining that i i had to re he rented
all this right he's got to send it back
after seven days or something and he had
to actually uh pay a twelve hundred
dollar deposit to actually rent this
thing and he gets to twelve hundred
bucks back when he ships the uh you know
the kit back and well you know fair
enough i guess um but you know like this
is not really something to complain
about like the individual is not going
to rent this kit right for seven days or
they're not going to buy it to fix their
one-off iphone they're just going to
take it to a repair center so i think
this is a pretty disingenuous uh rant
here from the verge it's not the point
like you know nobody's going to be dumb
enough to rent this kit and pay 1200
deposit and fix their iphone that's no
and they're still complaining after they
admit that apple would be making a loss
on this because apple actually pay the
uh postage both ways for these huge
pelican cases and yeah that would not be
cheap they offer free shipping in both
directions with your 49 rental so
they're complaining that you know look
there's no reason to complain and apple
are taking a loss on this by actually
even allowing you to rent these kits i
don't know why apple even uh bother
doing this but i think it's actually a
pretty good thing that they eat the cost
of the shipping on this and it's only 49
bucks to rent it even if you do have to
put the deposit down so i no no i i
don't agree that it's worth bashing
apple for that i expected apple would
send me a small box of screwdrivers
sponges and pliers i own my mini after
all instead they giant sent me giant a
pelican case and you know two pelican
cases 79 pounds of tools and all the
ring bound repair manual
why
complain about this you can't expect a
company like apple to just get like go
oh yeah here's some like a couple of
hand tools for you you know you have at
it um no they've actually done this
professionally and they've supplied like
they've done it in the absolute most
professional way possible the fact that
you actually um rented this professional
level
repair kit um and you're complaining
about it that no it's too professional
and no i shouldn't they shouldn't just
give me a spudger i can buy for a buck
on ebay delivered and a set of pliers i
can also buy for a buck on ebay
delivered and i think no come on it's
not fair so they're complaining here uh
what surprised me was the price tag 69
bucks for a new battery the same price
that apple store charges for a battery
replacement really i didn't know that it
was that cheap um that's actually really
good like if if apple are willing to
replace the battery in your iphone i
don't know never been to an apple store
in my life i've got no clue i've never
owned these fruity um apple gadgets um
but that that seems like a good deal so
yeah writing a whole article bashing
apple about this look i am not a fan of
apple but you know come on fair sucker
the sav right if it's 69 bucks and he
says except i get to do all the work and
assume all the risk well yeah you're the
one who wanted to do it so instead of
paying the 69 bucks to get it changed at
the i at the apple store so uh
49 bucks to rent apple's tool for a week
yeah that's freaking good
they're eating the cost of that and
making the service available why anyone
would wanna actually do it um i did i
don't know but geez you can't complain
about it seriously and he's complaining
about the 1200 credit card hold which
would forfeit if the tools won't return
within seven days well i i reckon that's
fair let's be clear this is a ridiculous
amount to risk for the average person
who just wants a new battery to put in
their phone um yeah and of course that's
why nobody is going to do this and this
is not really what right to repair what
the fundamental issues with right to
repair are i mean it's fantastic that
apple now let you get that just download
it from their website here it is here's
the link just download it you don't even
have to have an account i've got no
boom there it is right there's their
full 80 page repair manual absolutely
fantastic right and you can buy the
tools and the original parts right
absolutely fantastic sure it's not all
of them
but come on you've got to give apple
credit for like
at least
making these parts available and then
he's complaining about that he you know
went through the steps and repaired it
all and everything and then he uh you
know i put the screen back on with the
he's even the whole lot by the looks of
it and then it didn't
power up then he's complaining that
apple gave me no way to test whether the
battery in display connectors were
actually seated they probably won't have
and had me close up the phone anyhow
well i don't know maybe that's an issue
in the manual or something like that but
of course you obviously test it before
you go to the effort to seal the whole
phone up again surely you can like pair
it up with the screen dangling off or
something can't you i mean yeah i i
don't know this is not a fair suck of
the staff but this here is probably fair
criticism the single most frustrating
part of this process after using the
genuine past genuine tools was that the
iphone didn't recognize the battery the
genuine battery as genuine unknown part
flash to warning apparently that's the
case for almost all of these parts
you're expected to dial up apple's
third-party logistics company after the
repair so that they can validate the
part for you the process involves having
an entirely separate computer and wi-fi
connection since you have to reboot your
iphone in the diagnostics mode and give
the company remote control really um
yeah that that is an absolute joke come
on apple so let's get into the issues
with uh the right to repair and apple in
particular well
obviously that's one of them right i i
can't verify this myself but if that's
true then that's yeah that's just dumb
but the problem with apple and right to
repair and you'll hear this from louis
rossman all the time is that the biggest
problem is that they don't make board
level component repair easy in fact
apple in the past have tried to um you
know legally strong arm him um
not into actually releasing videos of
how to uh do it so i they don't release
schematics b they
actually have uh no cell agreements with
a lot of the uh
silicon manufacturers i believe are like
ti or somebody i can't name the exact
art ones but uh lewis does in his videos
but there are companies who manufacture
in specifically like the charger chips
in macbooks and things like that was
what lewis complains about all the time
they have no sell agreements for these
parts where you cannot buy them on
digikey now so anyway you cannot buy it
from the manufacturer from any
distributor whatsoever they only sell
the chip exclusively to apple and that's
one of the major problems they can't
even get their parts that's why uh
repair centers like louis rossman have
to
like strip old boards that like take
parts off old boards and things and put
them in and the third issue is um
component serialization like
they said down here you can't even put
in the
in this case the genuine batteries try
putting in a i don't know a third-party
battery or something like that but i'm
hearing that a lot of these components
like the third-party camera modules and
all sorts of things are individually
serialized and even if you take a a
genuine one out of another
iphone for example and put it in a and
put it in your iphone you buy it on ebay
it's a genuine part it came out of a
junk iphone because somebody i don't
know destroyed the thing and you go to
putting in yours it won't work because
of individual component serialization
the firmware checks the serial number
and goes
we don't want any part of that this is a
non-genuine part bugger off and yes of
course we can also talk about well they
should design these products so that
they're actually repairable the
batteries are replaceable and the
connectors are you know everything's
sort of like modular replaceable and all
that sort of stuff that is not the
argument because i they have to design
new products to do that and b well it's
the consumers that actually demand all
these you know sleeky wanky waterproof
bloody uh phones and everything that
have to be all glued shut sealed and
everything else so you know i can
understand the argument and i'm all for
it you know but people need to demand
these sort of things they have to stop
buying these fruity apple gadgets if
they're hard to repair so these are the
three major things that apple and other
manufacturers have to do if they're
serious about right to repair in
consumer products like this i mean but
seriously like hats off for apple
actually releasing all of this stuff and
being able to buy what what i think is
and these are incredible prices these
are amazingly low prices for these
genuine uh tools right so you know you
could argue yeah their display might be
a bit expensive at 100 and at 260 bucks
and stuff like that and i think uh lewis
has talked about um in the past like the
display the lcd itself like if you just
cracked the lcd you have to replace like
the entire assembly or something like
that um so they're you know they're and
they're only selling like a few parts at
the moment like i said but if you bust
like the connector in the thing then
well you've gotta like really get down
to like board level uh repair especially
if you've got a failed chip or something
like that i don't know how often like
chips in individual iphones uh fail but
then
macbooks are for example lewis has got a
whole
business you know with a dozen employees
or more dedicated just to fixing
macbooks um because of the and the chips
just fail in them with monotonous
regularity but of course you wouldn't
expect apple to like for their macbooks
once they have some things available for
them to have like individual charger
chips and stuff like that i think that's
asking too much of any company but they
at least they can do is to get rich
scrap those no sell agreements with the
uh semiconductor manufacturers so that
they can just make them available on
digikey or mouser and other suppliers
available on the free market so that you
can just buy them you know if you're a
repair business you buy a stock of you
know 100 of those charger chips because
you know they you know fail and then
you've got all your stock of all the
major parts uh that fail on hand and
scrap the serialization of
there's absolutely no reason to do it
and especially
when apple have basically said look you
can go and repair your own iphone now
right here's all the stuff to do it
here's all the info here's all the
official guide and everything and
obviously right i assume there's some
clause in there that you void your
warranty and everything else right and
that's fine and dandy everyone
understands that and so they're allowing
you to do this now in fact in even
encouraging you uh to repair your
own apple fruity gadget and so therefore
just like scrap all the other
about security and genuine parts and
everything else if people want to repair
them then they should be able to use any
third-party part without restriction
they should be able to use genuine parts
and and swap them between devices and
they should be able to buy the
semiconductor devices and they should be
able to get the schematics and don't
give me that bs about uh you know oh
company will just you know clone the
apple uh product because they've got the
schematics now
that's not how it works just release the
schematics and the board uh information
available in uh paul daniel's board view
software so that any repair shop can
just get his
software and then just load in the
genuine files and then troubleshoot to a
component level if they want to and then
the individual customers have the choice
if you want the genuine apple experience
you go into your apple fruity store and
you pay your thousand bucks to get
whatever fixed okay and or you can go to
your local uh
repair center authorized or not and they
will have access to a good lot of the
genuine parts and also third-party parts
and then the user has the choice whether
or not they want to uh you know risk
having like you know using little risk
scary uh third-party um you know screen
or something like that for a lower cost
and like seriously i don't know why
apple don't do this it's a no-brainer
but seriously this verge article just no
no it sucks it totally missed the mark
um
it's like no but hey it's the verge you
know anyway
leave your thoughts and comments down
below catch you next time
[Music]